A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, East European Fund FA747
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Community Files, 1951-1954; III
  - Philadelphia - Spot surveys, 1952 (Box 8)
  - San Francisco - International Institute Integration Project, 1953 (Box 8)
  - San Francisco - International Institute Integration Project, 1954 (Box 8)
  - San Francisco - International Institute Integration Project - Reports, 1953-1954 (Box 8)
  - San Francisco - International Institute Integration Project - Spot survey, 1952 (Box 8)
  - San Francisco Project - Questionnaire replies, 1954 (Box 8)
  - "The Special Projects of the EEF in the Field of Community Integration" - paper by David C. Munford, 1953 (Box 8)
  - Newsletters - Business, 1953-1954 (Box 8)
  - Newsletters - "Community Projects" no1, July 1953 (Box 8)
  - Newsletters - "Community Projects" no. 2, September 1953 (Box 8)
  - Newsletters - "Community Projects" no. 3, January 1954 (Box 8)
  - Newsletters - "Community Projects" no. 4, March 1954 (Box 8)
  - Newsletters - Distribution, 1953-1954 (Box 8)
- Grant Files, 1947-1956; IV
  The Grant Files are comprised of correspondence, grant applications and clippings. The grants were sought to fund such projects relating to the resettlement of ex-Soviet displaced persons and aid for emergency rehabilitation assistance to ex-Soviet exiled writers, artists, and scientists. The records also detail geographic specific programs like the New England Resettlement Center and the support for initial reception and resettlement of ex-Soviet displaced persons in the Boston area.
  - Grant Payment Cards, 1951-1952 (Box 8)
  - Grant Payment Cards, 1952-1953 (Box 8)
  - Grant Payment Cards, 1953-1956 (Box 8)
  - Grant Summaries, 1953-1954 (Box 9)
  - American Civic and Political Libra / American Constitution Handbook, 1952-1953 (Box 9)
  - American Slavic and East European Review / American Association for the Advancement of Slavic Studies, Inc., 1952-1953 (Box 9)
  - Bureau to Aid Ukrainians, 1951-1954 (Box 9)
  - Chekhov Publishing House - Chekhov Review Committee, 1953 (Box 9)
  - Church World Service of the National Council of the Churches of Christ in the USA, 1951-1954 (Box 9)
  - Committee for the Promotion of Advanced Cultural Slavic Studies, Inc., 1951-1953 (Box 9)
  - Committee for the Welfare of Cossack Displaced Persons in New Jersey (N. Korolkoff), 1951-1954 (Box 9)
  - Common Council for American Unity, 1951 (Box 9)
  - Common Council for American Unity, 1952-1953 (Box 9)
  - Common Council for American Unity, 1954 (Box 9)
  - Common Council for American Unity Orientation Handbook, 1953-1954 (Box 9)
  - Cossacks - Welfare Committee of the World Cossack Association, 1951-1952 (Box 9)
  - Cossacks - Welfare Committee of the World Cossack Association, 1951-1952 (Box 9)
    - Welfare Committee of the World Cossack Association, 1951-1952, 2015.035.002 (Item 2015:035:002)
  - Cossacks - Wefare Committee of the World Cossack Association, 1953-1954 (Box 9)
  - "Current Digest of the Soviet Press" - Social Science Research Council, 1952 (Box 9)
  - Directory of American Organizations of Exiles from the USSR, 1951-1952 (Box 9)
  - Directory of American Organizations of Exiles from the USSR, 1953 (Box 9)
  - Directory of American Organizations of Exiles from the USSR, 1954 (Box 9)
  - Don Cossack Chorus - The Society for the Relief of Russian War Invalids Outside of Russia, Inc., 1951-1954 (Box 9)
  - Francis Skoryna Kryvian Society of the Arts and Sciences in the USA, 1951-1952 (Box 9)
  - Francis Skoryna Kryvian Society of the Arts and Sciences in the USA, 1953 (Box 9)
  - Francis Skoryna Kryvian Society of the Arts and Sciences in the USA, 1954 (Box 9)
  - Free Russian Youth Club, 1951 (Box 9)
  - Free Russian Youth Club, 1952 (Box 9)
  - Free Russian Youth Club, 1953 (Box 9)
  - Free Russian Youth Club, 1954 (Box 9)
  - Fund for Intellectual Freedom, 1951-1953 (Box 9)
  - Georgian Association in the USA - Caucasian Relief Society, 1951-1953 (Box 9)
  - Humanity Calls, 1951 (Box 9)
  - Humanity Calls, 1952 (Box 9)
  - Humanity Calls, 1953 (Box 9)
  - Legal Aid Society - Support for adding Russian and Ukrainian speaking attorney to staff, 1951-1953 (Box 9)
  - Litfund - Aid for emergency rehabilitation assistance to ex-Soviet exile writers, artitst, scientists, 1951-1953 (Box 10)
  - National Committee for Resettlement of Foreign Physicians, 1952-1954 (Box 10)
  - New England Resettlement Center, 1951-1953 (Box 10)
  - New England Resettlement Center - photographs, 1951-1953 (Box 10)
    - St. Seraphim Foundation, 1951, photographs, 2015.035.003 (Item 2015:035:003)
  - New England Resettlement Center - printed matter, 1951-1952 (Box 10)
  - New Russian Theater - emergency payment to replace stolen properties, 1951-1952 (Box 10)
  - Novy Shurnal, The New Review - support for creative and itellectual activities of recent ex-Soviet exiles, 1951-1952 (Box 10)
  - Novy Shurnal, The New Review, 1953 (Box 10)
  - Novy Shurnal, The New Review, 1954 (Box 10)
  - ODUM (Ukrainian Democratic Youth Association), 1951-1952 (Box 10)
  - ODUM (Ukrainian Democratic Youth Association) (2 folders), 1953 (Box 10)
  - ODUM (Ukrainian Democratic Youth Association), 1954 (Box 10)
  - Roova Aid Bureau (Russian Consolidated Mutual Aid Society) - resettlement support, 1951-1952 (Box 10)
  - Roova Aid Bureau (Russian Consolidated Mutual Aid Society) - resettlement support, 1953 (Box 10)
  - Roova Aid Bureau (Russian Consolidated Mutual Aid Society) - resettlement support, 1954 (Box 10)
  - Russian Review - publication assistance, 1954 (Box 10)
  - Russian Student Fund, 1951 (Box 10)
  - Russian Student Fund, 1952 (Box 10)
  - Russian Student Fund, 1953 (Box 10)
  - Russian Student Fund, 1954 (Box 10)
  - St. Seraph Foundation - educational and cultural activities for young Soviet exiles, 1951 (Box 10)
  - New England Resettlement Center, 1951-1953, photographs and one neg, 2015.035 (Box 10)
    - New England Resettlement Center, 1951-1953, photographs and one neg, 2015.035.004 (Item 2015:035:004)
  - St. Seraph Foundation, 1952 (Box 10)
  - St. Seraph Foundation, 1953 (Box 10)
  - St. Seraph Foundation, 1954 (Box 10)
  - Shevchenko Scientific Society - aid in publication, 1953-1954 (Box 10)
  - Tolstoy Foundation - Aid in the reception and resettlement of ex-Soviet displaced persons, 1951 (Box 10)
  - Tolstoy Foundation - Aid in the reception and resettlement of ex-Soviet displaced persons, 1952 (Box 10)
  - Tolstoy Foundation - Aid in the reception and resettlement of ex-Soviet displaced persons, 1953 (Box 10)
  - Tolstoy Foundation - Aid in the reception and resettlement of ex-Soviet displaced persons, 1954 (Box 10)
  - Tolstoy Foundation - Literature (2 folders), 1947-1953 (Box 11)
  - Tolstoy Foundation - Reed Farm, 1950-1951 (Box 11)
  - Ukrainian Academy of Arts and Sciences in the US, Inc., 1951 (Box 11)
  - Ukrainian Academy of Arts and Sciences in the US, Inc., 1952 (Box 11)
  - Ukrainian Academy of Arts and Sciences in the US, Inc., 1953 (Box 11)
  - Ukrainian Academy of Arts and Sciences in the US, Inc., 1954 (Box 11)
  - Ukrainian-English Dictionary, University of Saskatchewan, 1952 (Box 11)
  - Ukrainian-English Dictionary, University of Saskatchewan, 1953-1954 (Box 11)
  - United Ukrainian American Relief Committee, 1953 (Box 11)
  - United Ukrainian American Relief Committee, 1954 (Box 11)
  - Whiteruthenian (Byelorussian) Institute of Arts and Sciences - support for publication, 1952-1954 (Box 11)
  - YMCA: Vocational Service Center Branch, 1953-1954 (Box 11)
- Scholarship Program, 1952-1955; V
  The arrangement is alphabetical by last name and includes the college or university the applicant is attending.
  The East European Fund’s Scholarship Program supported Ukrainian and Byelorussian exiles attending American colleges and universities. This series consists of administrative records for the winners and rejected applications spanning 1952 to 1955.
  All of the student files in this series contain personal information about the students recieving the scholarships.
  - Scholarships - General, 1952-1953 (Box 11)
  - Scholarships - General - Ukranian Studend Fund Advisory Committee, 1952-1953 (Box 11)
  - Scholarships - General - Ukranian Studend Fund grants, 1952-1953 (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Afendykiw, Marko (Detroit) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Chajkovskyj, Oleh (Ukrainian Scholarship) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Cherkaskij, Odnynce, Dmytro (Ukrainian Scholarship) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Dutka, Orest J. (Ukrainian Scholarship) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Dzerowycz, Arian (New York City) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Fedyshyn, Oleh J. (Ukrainian Scholarship) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Flipovich, Orest Nichols (Minneapolis) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Hawryluk, Orest (Ukraine) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Hnatyszyn, Myzoslav (Ukrainian Scholarship) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Huebner, Leonid (Ukrainian Scholarship) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Jerschkowsky, Oleg (Utica, NY) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Karapinka, George (Ukraine) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Kociuba, Lubomyr (Ukrainian Scholarship) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Kulchycka, Lydia W. (Ukrainian Scholarship) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Makhov, George (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Nechay, Bohdan (Minneapolis) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Petrov, Mirtala (Ukraine) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Petryszyn, Volodymyr (Ukraine) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Pihut, Bohdan J. (Ukraine) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Pundyk, George (Ukraine) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Sevcenko, Oxana (Ukraine) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Sharko, Wolodymyr (Ukraine) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Smolansky, Oles (Ukraine) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Stachiw, Yaroslaw (Ukraine) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Sxylo, Raisa (Ukraine) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Terleckyj, Nestor E. (Ukraine) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Tkacz, Jaroslaw (Ukraine) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Wolowodiuk, Walter (Ukraine) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Yaworsky, Yaroslaus J. (Ukraine) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Zajciw, Leonid (Ukraine) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Student - Zielyk, Ihor V. (Ukraine) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1953 - Candidate Reviews - Okinshevich, Dr. Leo (Box 13)
  - 1952-1953 - General correspondence (Box 11)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Afendykiw, Marko (Detroit) (Box 11)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Arcivch, Joseph (Brooklyn Polytechnic Inst.) (Box 11)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Bandera, Volodimir (U. of Connecticut) (Box 11)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Basiuk, Victor (Columbia University) (Box 11)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Bilan, Mykyta V. (Duke University) (Box 11)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Chajkowskyj, Oleh (University of Buffalo) (Box 11)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Danczenko, Witaly (Berea College, KY) (Box 11)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Dutka, Orest J. (North Carolina State College) (Box 11)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Dzerowycz, Arian (Box 11)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Fedyshyn, Oleh (Columbia University) (Box 11)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Gladyszowski, Nadia (Long Island, NY) (Box 11)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Hnatyszyn, Myroslav (NYU) (Box 11)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Hrycak, Paul V. (University of Minnesota) (Box 11)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Huebner, Leonid (University of Illinois) (Box 11)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Jaroszewicz, Olga (Colby College, Maine) (Box 11)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Jerschkowsky, Oleg (Syracuse University) (Box 11)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Karapinka, George (Seton Hall University) (Box 11)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Kociuba, Lubomyr (Pennsylvania Mil. College) (Box 11)
  - 1952-1954 - Candidate Reviews - Odlozilik, Professor Otakar (Box 13)
  - 1952-1954 - Candidate Reviews - Fedynski, Dr. Jurij (Box 13)
  - Candidate Reviews - Luckyj, Dr. George (Box 13)
    - 1952-1954 - Candidate Reviews - Okinshevich, Dr. Leo (Box 13)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Kryzanowsky, Julian (University of Connecticut) (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Kulchycka, Lydia W. (University of Pittsburgh) (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Kwiatkowsky, Maria (Mrs.) (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Lewizky, Jury (Wayne University) (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Lubaczo, Iwan (Ohio State University) (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Macyk, George (NYU) (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Makhov, George (Wayne University) (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Paclawskyj, Orest (NYU) (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Petrov, Mirtala (School of the Museum of Fine Arts) (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Petryszyn, Volodymyr (Columbia University) (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Pundyk, Youry M. (University of Minnesota) (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Rozhin, Jurij (Wayne University) (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Sapankevych, Zina (NJ College for Women) (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Sevcenko, Oxana (Columbia University) (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Sharko, Wolodymer (Ohio Northern University) (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Skina, Valentina (Bucknell University) (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Smolansky, Oles (Columbia University) (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Stachiw, Yaroslaw (Oklahoma A (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Szylo, Raisa (Columbia University) (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Terlecka, Lidia (Wayne University) (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Terleckyj, Nestor (Columbia University) (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Wasylkiwsky, Eugenia (Columbia University) (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Wytanowycz, A. (University of Chicago) (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Yaroslaus J., Yaworsky (Newark College of Engineering) (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Zajciw, Leonid (Wayne University) (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Zielyk, Ihor V. (Seton Hall University) (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Student - Zotowska, Anna (Columbia University) (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Advisory Committee (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Basic materials (Box 12)
  - 1953-1954 - Payments (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Afendykiw, Marko (Wayne University) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Archiuch, Joseph (Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Bakum, Raisa S. (Columbia University) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Bandera, Jaroslav (University of Vermont) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Bandera, Volodimir (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Basiuk, Victor (Columbia University) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Bilan, Mykyta (Duke University) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Chajkovskyj, Oleh (University of Buffalo) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Danczenko, Witaly (MIT) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Fedyshyn, Oleh (Columbia University) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Gladyszowsky, Nadia (Long Island University) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Harkawy, Natalia (Swarthmore) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Honchariw, James (Columbia University) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Huebner, Leonid (University of Chicago) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Jaroszewicz, Olga (Colby College, Maine) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Jerschkowsky, Oleg (Syracuse University) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Jurevitch, Olga (De Paul University) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Kamenetsky, Ihor (University of Illinois) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Karapinka, George (Seton Hall University) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Kindrat, Iwan (NYU) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Kochno, Katherine M. (Columbia University) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Kryzanowsky, Julian (University of Connecticut) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Kuchor, Roman V. (University of Colorado) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Kulchycka, Lydia (University of Pittsburgh) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Kwiatkowsky, Maria (Wayne University) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Kyzyk, Ivan (NYU) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Lewizky, Jury (Wayne University) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Lubaczko, Iwan (Ohio State) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Nicolayevitch, Ani (Columbia University) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Nimylowycz, Jurij (Perdue University) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Odarchenko, Alexander (George Washington University) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Olchowyj, George (Brooklyn Polytechnic Institute) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Orlowsky, Nataloe (Grove City College, PA) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Paclawskyj, Orest (NYU_ (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Petryshyn, Walter (Columbia University) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Pelech, Ivan (Case Institute of Technology) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Plujko, Borys (Case Institute of Technology) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Rozhin, Jurij (Wayne University) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Rubczak, Bohdan (University of Illinois) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Sich, Dmytro (Rutgers University) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Smolansky, Oles (Columbia University) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Stachiw, Yaroslaw (Oklahoma A (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Stecura, Stephan (Western Reserve University) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Terlecka, Lidia (Wayne University) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Terleckyj, Nestor (Columbia University) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Woroch, Stephen (NYU) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Wytanowicz, Areta M. (University of Chicago) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Yanchishin, John (Michigan State College) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Yaworsky, Yaroslaus (Newark College of Engineering) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Zielyk, Ivor V. (Seton Hall University) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Student - Zotowska, Anna (Columbia University) (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - General (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - General - basic materials (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Program correspondence (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Program selection committee (Box 12)
  - 1954-1955 - Scholarships and administrative expenses (Box 12)